Annette Kar Baxter Papers, 1905-1984
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1959-83
  - Friends and associates
    - Blair, Karen, 1980-82, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS--Contributions to books, Clubwoman As Feminist] (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Boorse, Henry, 1960-81, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Breunig, Leroy C., 1970-76, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Burden, Carter, 1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Burns, Kathy, [see Kathy Burns Schrader] (Box 10)
    - C, 1959-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Carnes, Mark, 1982-83, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Chafe, Bill, 1978-79 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Chambers, John, 1974-82, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Conway, Jill, 1982, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS-Education--Smith College] (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Costikyan family, 1969-82 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Cott, Nancy, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Crisp, Eleanor and Jack, 1959-69 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Cross, Barbara and Robert, 1965-70, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS--Unpublished writings-Monographs--The Child in America; Tributes] (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - D, 1961-83 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Densen-Gerber, Judianne, 1971-72 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Dobkin, Marge, 1961-83, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - E, 1960-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Elliott, Eleanor, 1969-82, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Elsberg, Constance N. Waeber, 1966-80 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - F, 1960-82, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Fagan, Ann, 1972-76, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 11, Folder 2)
      [Closed until 2035]
    - Farkas, Suzanne and Robin, 1968-72, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Fass, Paula, 1966-82 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Field, Daniel, 1976, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Fleming, Donald, 1959-82 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Frank, Ruth, 1973-76, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Frankel, Toby, 1974-79 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Freeman, Marge, [see Marge Freeman Harrison] (Box 11)
    - Freedman, Estelle, 1969-81, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Futter, Ellen, 1980-82 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - G, 1964-83 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Gatje, Barbara and Robert and family, 1962-78 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Gillespie, Louise L., [see Louise L. Gillespie Stevenson] (Box 11)
    - Goldberg, Robert, 1972-76 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Gordon, Bill, 1963-72, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Gordon, Carol, 1959-72 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Gordon, Lynn, 1977-81, [see also SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES-Organizations and Conferences-American Historical Association-Panel Proposal] (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Gould, Jane, 1971-83, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Gould, Sarah E., 1979-82 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Graff, Ellen, 1971-77, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Graham, Pat and Loren, 1968-72 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Griffith, Lucille, 1959-71 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - H, 1961-83, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Hall, David, 1973-82, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Hall, Jacqueline, 1970-75 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Hamalian, Leo, 1965-75 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Hansl, Eva, 1967-68 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Harrington, Virginia, 1962-82, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Harrison, Marge Freeman, 1974-78 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Hathaway, Robert, 1982-83 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Haverstick, Iola and family, 1970-83, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Hechinger, Grace, 1971-75 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Hofstadter, Bea and Richard, 1970-71, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - J, 1966-82 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Janeway, Elizabeth, 1972-80, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Jaffe, Irma, 1969-71 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Jong, Erica, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - K, 1962-83, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Kalibbala, Norma Livingston, 1973-75 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kaufman, Helen L., 1966-69 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Kempsell, George, 1962-63, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Kerber, Linda K., 1964-80, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Kluge, Svetlana, 1962-73, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Koss, Stephen, 1969, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Kouvenhaven, John, 1962-81 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - L, 1960-81, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Labalme, Patricia, 1960-75, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Laden, Vicki, 1972-73 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Larrabee, Harold and family, 1959-71, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Levy, Darline, 1973-83, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Linden, Janine, 1979-82, undated, [see also SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES-Organizations and conferences-Compton Digest] (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Livingston, Norma, [see Norma Livingston Kalibbala] (Box 12)
    - Losee, Carole, 1973-81 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Long, Pamela, 1982-83 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Lowe, Ann Wenig, 1968-72 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - M, 1961-83, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Malement, Barbara, 1976-79 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Mandel family, 1959-82 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Marcus, Celine, 1979-83 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Marstellar, Julie, 1968-79, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Martineau, Barbara, 1966-73, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - McCaughey, Bob, 1969-82, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - McIntosh, Millicent, 1960-80, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE; SERIES VII. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES- Job opportunities-Sarah Lawrence College; Organizations and conferences-Bryn Mawr; Kirkland College] (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Jeannie, 1972-81, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Murdoch, Mary-Elizabeth, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - N, 1960-82, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Nelbach, Inez. G., 1961-72, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Nelson, Peggy, 1972-73 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - O, 1964-83 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Oberholzer, Emil, 1964-75 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - P, 1959-83 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Park, Rosemary, 1962-81, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Peterson, Martha, 1963-75, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Pockman, Lee, 1962-80, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Q, 1968-74 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - R, 1959-81 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Rauch, Basil, 1959-82, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Rendigs, Chuck Jr., 1981-82, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Robinson, Michael, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Rockland, Michael, 1977-82, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS--Unpublished writings-Monographs--Foreign Views of American Women] (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Rosenblum, Naomi, 1977-81 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Ryan, William, 1959-68 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - S, 1960-83, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Sabre, Nancy, 1959-70 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Sanford, John, 1980-82, n.d (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Santore, John, 1980-82, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Schlissel, Lillian, 1974-81 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Schrader, Kathy Burns, 1972-74 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Scott, Anne Firor, 1968-69 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Selby, Cecily, 1971-78, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Shange, Nzotake, [see Paulette Williams] (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Shikoh, Jane Allen, 1972-82 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Sicherman, Barbara, 1975-82 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Sprague, Claire, 1968-75, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Srebnik, Amy, 1981-83 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Stearns, Winifred, 1971-82 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Stevenson, Louise L. Gillespie, 1970-83, undated, [see also SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES-Organizations and conferences-American Studies Association-Panel proposal] (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Stewart, Peg Wright, 1981-82 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Stimson, Catherine, 1973-74, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Stix, Carol, 1964-71, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Sturtevant, Susan Armeny, 1976-81 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - T, 1960-83, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Tananbaum, Duane, 1982, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Thomas, Cammy, 1972-74 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - U, 1962, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - V, 1960-82, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - W, 1961-83, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Waeber, Constance N., [see Constance N. Waeber Elsberg] (Box 14)
    - Weiner, Cheryl, 1970-71, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Welter, Barbara, 1968-75, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS--Unpublished writings-Monographs] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      [Closed]
    - Wemple, Susanne (and family), 1971-82, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Wenig, Ann, [see Ann Wenig Lowe] (Box 14)
    - Wensberg, Erik, 1961-75, [See also SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS--Columbia University Forum] (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - White, Penny Conrad, 1970-73, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Whitney, Frances, 1960-68, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Williams, Paulette [Ntozake Shange], 1970-71 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Williamson, Chilton and Elizabeth, 1960-83, undated, [see also SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE] (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Wright, Margaret (Peg), [see Peg Wright Stewart] (Box 14)
    - Y, 1973-81 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Yoffe, Amy J., 1971-73 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Z, 1972-80 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified, 1959-83, undated (Box 15, Folder 4-7)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS 1963-88
  - Monographs (Box 15)
    - Henry Miller, Expatriate: book review, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - To Be a Woman in America, 1850-1930, [see also SERIES VIII. OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
      - Contracts and sales, 1978-82 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Captions, undated (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
      - Drafts of manuscript, 1979, undated (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
      - Reviews, advertisements, and reactions by readers, 1978-79, undated (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - Inwood House, 1839-1980
      - Correspondence, 1979-80 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Notes, 1941-80, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Contributions to monographs, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
      - Drafts, undated (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
      - Published version, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Archetypes of American Innocence: Lydia Blood and Daisy Miller," chapter in The American Experience ed. by Hennig Cohen, 1966, [see also Articles] (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Introduction, The Universal Self-Instructor, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Dorsey Press
      - General, 1975-82 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Breaking through the Male Barrier," chapter in Men, Women, and Issues in American History, vol. 2, 1975, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "American Women from 1876 to the Present: The Search for Identity," chapter in Main Problems in American History, vol. 2, 4th ed, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Preface, Clubwoman As Feminist: True Womanhood Redefined, 1868-1914 by Karen J. Blair, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Foreword, To Feed Their Hopes: A Book of American Women by John Sanford, 1980, [see also Unpublished materials-Reviews of others' works-Identified-University of Illinois Press-To Feed Their Hopes] (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Women's Education and Women's Values," chapter in Race, National Origin, and Gender Desegregation in Public Education: Political, Social, and Policy Issues, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Series edited
    - Co-editor, American Women: Images and Realities, 44 vols. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Co-editor, Women in America: From Colonial Times to the 20th Century, 59 vols. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Co-editor, and general introduction, Signal Lives: Autobiographies of American Women, 51 vols.
      - Correspondence, 1978-80 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Notes, 1978-79, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Introductions, 1979, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Publicity, 1979, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Editor-in-chief, Landmark Dissertations in Women's Studies
      - Arno Press (Box 18)
        - General, 1978-81, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Data sheets, 1980, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Garland Publishing, 1980-82, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Praeger
        - Correspondence, 1982-83 (Box 18, Folder 10)
        - Notes, 1983, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Royalty Statements, 1981-82 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Articles
    - "Archetypes of American Innocence: Lydia Blood and Daisy Miller," American Quarterly, Spring 1953, [see also Contributions to books] (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Independence versus Isolation: Hawthorne and James on the Problems of the Artist," Nineteenth Century Fiction, Dec 1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Elvis: The Man in the Blue Suede Shoes," with James E. Baxter, Harper's Magazine, Jan 1958 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Freedom: Fun and Games," with James Baxter, Columbia University Forum, Summer 1961, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Caste and Class: Howell's Boston and Wharton's New York," The Midwest Quarterly, Summer 1963 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "Henry Miller and Henry James: An Imaginary Correspondence on the Morality of the Artist," Ararat, Autumn 1963 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Looking at the Literary Twenties," Ararat, Winter 1964 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "The College's Leading Women and their Roles: An Interpretation," BARNARD COLLEGE Alumnae Magazine, Spring 1964 (reprinted in Congressional Record Appendix), 19 May 1964 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "Searching for the Lost Sex," Ararat, Winter 1969 (reprinted in Barnard College Alumnae Magazine), Summer 1969 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Is Gloria Steinem Dead?" Newsweek, 2 Sep 1974 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Women's Studies and American Studies: The Use of the Interdisciplinary," American Quarterly, Oct 1974 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Perspectives," The Independent School Bulletin, Oct 1975 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "On Women's Colleges," Op. Ed. page, The New York Times, 21 Jan 1978 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Notes for articles, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Invitations to write articles, 1959-80 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Encyclopedia entries, [see also SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES]
    - Encyclopedia Britannica: Henry Miller, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Notable American Women, 1971
      - Isadora Duncan (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Sarah Porter (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Emily Putnam (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Dictionary of American Biography: Mary Emma Woolley, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Encyclopedia of American Women, 1974
      - Mary Lyon (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Amy Lowell (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Notable American Women: The Modern Period: Virginia Crocheron Gildersleeve, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Declined offers, 1968-73 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Book reviews
    - Edith Wharton: Convention and Morality in the Work of a Novelist by Marilyn Jones Lyde in Journal of the Central Mississippi Valley American Studies Association, Spring 1961 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Beer Can by the Highway by John Kouwenhoven in Barnard College Alumnae Magazine, Winter 1962 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "Random Brushstrokes of a Radical Optimist" (double review of Henry Miller: Watercolors, Drawings and His Essay, "The Angel is in My Watermark," and Stand Still Like the Hummingbird by Henry Miller), New York Times Book Review, 8 Jul 1962 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Arshile Gorky by Harold Rosenberg, Ararat, Summer 1962 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - The Bewildered Age by V.P. Held in Barnard College Alumnae Magazine, Fall 1962 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - In Search of Greatness by Yousuf Karsh in Ararat, Spring 1963 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - A Backward Glance by Edith Wharton in New York Times Book Review, 9 Aug 1964 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - The Man Bilbo by A. Wigfall Green in Political Science Quarterly, Sep 1964 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - The John Birch Society: Anatomy of a Protest by John Robinson in The Parish Messenger, Jun 1964 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Vernon Lee: Violet Paget, 1856-1935 by Peter Gunn in Victorian Studies, Jun 1965 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - "Pleasure and Pains: The Two Lives of Edith Wharton: The Woman and Her Work" by Grace Kellogg in The New York Times Book Review, 28 Nov 1965 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "An Organic Concept of Life," Ararat, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - A Mother in History by Jean Stafford in New York Times Book Review, 13 Mar 1966 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Mind and Art of Henry Miller by William Gordon in New York Times Book Review, 15 Oct 1967 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - The Fighting Pankhursts by David Mitchell in New York Times Book Review, 7 Jan 1968 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Black Power: The Politics of Liberation in America by Stokely Carmichael and Charles V. Hamilton in Political Science Quarterly, Dec 1968 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Samuel Griswold Goodrich by Daniel Roselle in The American Historical Review, Oct 1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - The Child and the Republic by Bernard Wishy in New York Historical Society Quarterly, Jan 1971 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Double review of A Formula of His Own: Henry Adams' Literary Experiment by John J. Conder, and Symbol and Idea in Henry Adams by Melvin Lyon in American Historical Review, Apr 1971 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - The Life of Ezra Pound by Noel Stock in American Historical Review, Apr 1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Double review of The Woman Citizen: Social Feminism in the 1920s by J. Stanley Lemons, and Women, Resistance and Revolution by Shelia Rowbotham in Political Science Quarterly, Dec 1973 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Mary Todd Lincoln: Her Life in Letters by Justin G. and Linda Levitt Turner in American Historical Review, Jun 1974 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Mary Wollstonecraft by Eleanor Flexner in Women's Studies, Fall 1974 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Woman's Consciousness, Man's World by Sheila Rowbotham in Political Science Quarterly, Fall 1974 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Women's Studies and American Studies: The Uses of the Interdisciplinary," review essay of The Novels of Harriet Beecher Stowe by Alice Crozier and The Oven Birds: Women on Womanhood in American Quarterly, Oct 1974 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - A Minority of Members: Women in the U.S. Congress by Hope Chamberlain in The Social Studies, Mar/Apr 1975 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Hidden from History by Sheila Rowbotham in Political Science Quarterly, Winter 1975-76 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Women and Equality: Changing Patterns in American Culture by William H. Chafe in Political Science Quarterly, Spring 1978 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - The Female Experience: An American Documentary by Gerda Lerner in The New York Historical Society Quarterly, Jul 1978 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - The Half-Opened Door: Discrimination and Admissions at Harvard, Yale, and Princeton, 1900-70 by Marcia Graham Synnott in The Journal of American History, Jun 1980 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - A Timeless Affair: The Life of Anita McCormick Blaine by Gilbert A. Harrison in The American Historical Review, Oct 1980 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - "Myths, Mediums and Money: The Transformation of Evangelicalism," review essay, Mission for Life by Joan Jacobs Brumberg in Reviews in American History, Dec 1981 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Double review, Mary Lyon and Mount Holyoke: Opening the Gates by Elizabeth Alden Green, and The Making of a Feminist: Early Journals and Letters of M. Carey Thomas ed. by Marjorie H. Dobkin in Labor History, Winter 1982 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Wage-Earning Women: Industrial Work and Family Life in the United States, 1900-1930 by Leslie W. Tentler, in The New York Historical Society Quarterly, Spring 1982 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - "Good Man's Poor Wife": Being a Chronicle of Harriet Hanson Robinson and her Family in Nineteenth Century New England by Claudia L. Bushman in The Journal of American History, Jun 1982 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Double review, European Women on the Left: Socialism, Feminism, and the Problems Faced By Political Women, 1880 to the Present ed. by Jane Slaughter and Robert Kern, and Women and American Socialism, 1870-1920 by Mari Jo Buhle in Political Science Quarterly, Spring 1983 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Daughters of the State: A Social Portrait of the First Reform School for Girls in North America, 1856-1905 by Barbara Brenzel in The Women's Review of Books, Nov 1983 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Woman's Worth: Sexual Economics and the World of Women by Lisa Leghorn and Katherine Parker in Labor History, Spring 1984 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Double review, Edwardian Childhoods by Thea Thompson, and Girls Growing Up in Late Victorian and Edwardian England by Carol Dyhouse in History of Education Quarterly, Spring 1984 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Requests to review books, 1968-83, undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1963-83, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - "Women in Politics" exhibit
    - Correspondence, 1963-64 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Notes, 1963, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Background information, 1956-64, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Herman/Tilton Bicentennial exhibit, 1954, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Drafts of captions, undated (Box 22, Folder 5-22)
    - Outline with captions, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Comments from others re: outline, 1963-64, undated (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Articles and press releases, 1963-64 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Tributes, letters to the editor, interviews, and miscellaneous statements, 1957-75, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 22, Folder 26-29)
  - Unpublished materials
    - Monographs (Box 23)
      - The Child in America (with Barbara Cross), 1967-68 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - History of the American Association of University Women, circa 1968-76, undated, [see also SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS-American Association of University Women] (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Foreign Views of American Women (with Michael Rockland), 1973-80, undated
        - Correspondence, 1973-80, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Drafts, 1975, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - Notes
          - General, 1974, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
          - A-M (Box 23, Folder 6-31)
          - N-Z (Box 24, Folder 1-12)
          - Subjects (Box 24, Folder 13)
          - Dates to be ascertained (Box 24, Folder 14)
          - Discards (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - American history textbook for junior and senior college, with John Chambers, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Comparative Study of Women's Organizations (with Barbara Welter), 1982, undated, [see also SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES-Women--Clubs] (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Women's History Reading Lists (with Barbara Welter), 1972-84 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Revisionism and Women's History: An Historiographical Study, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Articles
      - "Betty Friedan, Feminine Mystique," 1963 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - "Privacy," 1963, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - "Pressures on Women," 1965, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - "Thoughts on Women's Studies at Barnard College," 1972 (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - "Academic Scene," undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - " A Constable of the Forties," undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - "Concealment and Revelation," undated (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Book reviews: Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosche by Henry Miller (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous fiction, undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Baxter-Dintenfass project, undated (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Potential future publications, 1963-83, undated (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
    - Reviews of others' works